hello everyone my name is Greg and I Dev
stuff welcome everyone to Episode 22 of
tactus game in unity Victory condition
and assorted fixes
today we want to introduce a way to win
scenario select game manager and create
another new component called Victory
condition manager
this component will be responsible for
tracking Victory conditions for player
and enemy
let's begin by implementing simple
Victory condition for the player let's
say we need to defeat all the enemy
pawns on the field to win make a
reference field for Force container
called enemy Force which will reference
well enemy Force container
reference the enemy force and the editor
good
inside Victory condition manager let's
make a new method called check player
victory
inside check player Victory we want to
set up condition for victory which for
now will be simple defeat of all enemy
we have a list of all participants in
the enemy Force inside the force
container but this is stored just as a
character turn component and to check if
the character defeated or not we need to
get the character component
let's change our container a little
let's introduce Force member class which
will store reference to the character
and character tour
use it in the force container to store
references for each member of the force
let's rename parameter into character
tour to avoid confusion with character
component
fix the ground turn
good now we can create a new method
called check defeated which redurant
blue type
where we will determine if this Force
has been defeated or not where we will
cycle through every first member and if
at least one of them is not defeated
that mean the entire force is not yet
defeated
good now in Victory condition for player
check if the enemy Force has been
defeated if yes post message into debug
log
now we need to call check player Victory
when enemy are getting defeated to check
if we completed the stage after
defeating the enemy we will do it from
command manager enemy can be defeated
only after getting attacked so for now
the best place to check for all Enemy
being defeated con Victory condition is
after attack command execution
after each attack command execution I
want to check the winning condition
to be able to do the scarce the victory
condition manager
and then in attack command execution
call for check of Victory condition
this is not very optimal it is better to
check only in case the target is dead we
will be optimizing gaming later on in
the tutorial
let's tell this
let's delete unnecessary enemies leaving
only one and make him weak
good
support of people on patreon and members
on YouTube if you want to join them link
to my patreon in the description and
join button available right now on
YouTube
we have a problem after attack enemy
object is getting selected
inside select character create blue
variable called is selected
when select something set it to be true
and then in the select set it to be
false instead of setting selected to be
null
and inside the late update if we have
selected object and is selected set to
be false after the call to deselect we
want to set selected object to be no
this way we will prevent a select
character to try to select the object on
the same frame as as we deselected the
object
good that fixes the problem
after moving into the area we can't
immediately click on the spot and select
the character without moving the mouse
I am right now clicking like Starcraft
player and on the spot and nothing is
happening I need to move my mouse away
and hover over the spot again to be able
to select
this is happening because of our
optimization inside select character we
only update the hover over object by our
Mouse when we move the mouse around so
let's move the check for moved mouse
outside the hover over object detection
method
and now inside the select character
explicitly call hover over object to
force our select object to check if
there is something we are currently
hovering over when you click to select
something
this should fix the issue we're having
good it works now
good this is it for this episode if you
have any questions or any ideas about
code please leave your comment below if
you want to support further link to my
patreon in the description special thank
you to
each May and this old hash do with best
regards see in the next episode